I'm gonna ask a question that will
confuse you but it is a title of the
sermon and that is why did you laugh why
did you laugh so I'm gonna ask it again
do you believe that Jesus is coming
again and my question again is why did
you laugh I invite you to turn your
Bibles to the book of Genesis chapter 18
Genesis chapter 18 and we are going to
begin reading from verse 1 Genesis 18
verse 1 when you're there let me hear
you say Amen the Bible says and the Lord
appeared unto him and the plains of
Marmora and he sat in the tent door in
the heat of the day and he lifted up his
eyes and looked and lo three men stood
by him and when he saw them he ran to
meet them from the tent door and bowed
himself to the ground and said my lord
if now I have found favor in thy sight
pass not away I pray thee from thy
servant let a little water I pray you be
fetched fetched and wash your feet and
rest yourselves under the tree and I
will fetch a morsel of bread and comfort
you your hearts after that you shall
apat you shall pass on for therefore are
you come to your servant and they said
so do as thou has said and Abraham
hastened into the tent unto Sarah
and said make ready quickly three
measures of fine meal knead it and make
cakes upon the earth and Abraham ran
unto the herd and fetched a calf tender
and good and gave it unto a young man
and he hasted to dress it and he took
butter and milk and the calf which he
had dressed and set it before them and
he stood by them under the tree and they
did eat and they said unto Him where is
Sarah thy wife and he said Behold in the
tent and he said I will certainly return
unto thee according to the time of life
and lo Sarah thy wife
shall have a son and Sarah heard it in
the tent door which was behind him now
Abraham and Sarah will old and well
stricken in age and it seems to be with
Sarah after the manner of women
therefore Sarah laughed out loud
I read that again therefore Sara laughed
out loud
she laughed how within herself it wasn't
a loud laugh because that would have
revealed doubt so being a good
seventh-day adventists she laughed
but on the inside saying after I am
waxed old shall I have pleasure my lord
being old also and the Lord said unto
Abraham wherefore did Sarah laugh saying
shall I ever surely bear a child which
I'm old is anything too hard for the
Lord at the term appointed I will return
unto thee according to the time of life
and Sarah shall have a son then Sarah
denied what she do everyone she looked
strangely at the pastor when he asked
why did you laugh then Sarah denied
saying I laugh not for she was what a
freeing and he said nay but thou didst
laugh you did laughs Sarah you laughed
you laughed at the promise of God now
you know we're probably thinking yes
this was Sarah you know and maybe she
was weak in faith and her husband
probably had to encourage her you know
to stand strong because Abraham of
course is the father of faith amen amen
amen
except if you go that one chapter to
chapter 17 you'll notice
something very interesting in chapter 17
God is speaking to Abraham and in verse
15 it says God said unto Abraham after
Sarah thy wife thou shalt not call her
name Sarai but Sarah shall be her name
and I will bless her and give thee a son
also of her yeah I will bless her and
she shall be a mother of Nations kings
of people shall be upon her then Abraham
fell upon his face and laughed Sarah had
the decency to do it on the inside but
Abraham the father of faith laughed out
loud the verse says that he said in this
heart shall a child be born unto him
that is a hundred years old and shall
Sarah that is ninety-nine years old
there and Abraham said unto God
oh that Ishmael might live before thee I
have a question for you very quickly I
just want you to keep this point in mind
abraham thought that ishmael was the
fulfillment of the promise are you with
me I need you to catch that and I need
you to listen to that carefully tuck
that away in your mind abraham thought
that ishmael was a fulfillment of the
promise of god let me ask you a question
why are they laughing
Abraham is 99 years old at this time the
Bible tells us that it was many years
earlier that God had come to Abraham and
given him the promise that they were to
have a child in fact come back with me
to Genesis chapter 12 and verse 4
Genesis chapter 12 and verse 4 the Bible
says so Abraham departed and the Lord
spoke unto him and lot went with him and
Abraham was seventy and five years old
when he departed out of Haran so Abraham
was 75 years old when he was given this
promise and I want you to imagine just
just think with me for a moment
Abraham has been given this promise he's
75 years old and God says you're gonna
have a child you are going to be the
father of a great nation and so uh in
its at 75 years old how do you think
Abraham is feeling how do you think
Abraham and Sarah are feeling yes God's
Word have spoken God said we're gonna
have a child God said it I believe it
that settles it amen eight months come
and go and people are asking Abraham and
Sarah hey you know what you know what's
up are you sure God spoke to you and
they probably rebuked them saying how
dare you this is the Word of God God's
Word will stand firm God said it that
settles it I believe it amen
three years pass don't worry God may be
late but he's always on time seven years
fast
keep the faith brother
keep the faith 10 years past 12 years
past 18 years past 20 years past 25
years past and now when the promise is
repeated to them what are they doing
they're laughing have you ever laughed
at the promise of God that laughter in
in Genesis chapter 18 has some some some
context that I want you to get that I
want you to understand it has a
prophetic context and I need you to see
this and in order to see this we're
going to go all the way back to the
beginning of the Bible and we're going
to go to Genesis chapter 1 you don't
need to turn there but we know that in
Genesis chapters 1 and 2 we have the
creation of the earth in Genesis chapter
3 we have the fall of man in Genesis
chapter 4 we have Cain killing Abel in
Genesis chapter 5 and 6 or rabbit
chapter 6 we have the introduction of a
man by the name of Noah and and in
Genesis chapter 6 God is about to give a
prophecy to this prophet named Noah and
the prophecy is that after a certain
time the world is going to be flooded
how much time was there how much time
was Noah giving to preach 120 years and
the Bible tells us that that during this
120 years that Noah was preaching he was
building an ark to prepare for the flood
now I want you to notice something here
we're in Genesis chapter 6 we're gonna
work our way back to Genesis chapter 18
but in Genesis chapter 6 you may not
have realizes in Genesis chapter 6 we
have the first time prophecy of the Old
Testament how many of you knew that how
many of you never thought about that in
Genesis chapter 6 you have the first
time prophecy of the Old Testament it is
120 years that Noah is given to preach
now
want you to notice something about this
time prophecy this time prophecy was a
prophecy of mercy of one everyone mercy
God was giving a probationary time
period to a group of people who listened
carefully if they were if they rejected
the message that had come to them they
were going to be cut off and God was
going to bring a new people about does
that prophecy sound familiar to you just
hold on for a second remember that at
the end of this are preaching time
that's 120 years
remember that Noah gets into an ark
built of wood and the rain lifts that
wood up above the earth so in essence at
the end of this time prophecy you have a
man preaching a message of salvation who
has ultimately lifted up above the earth
on wood and those who reject him are cut
off and a new people are raised upon the
scene whose mission it is to spread
around the world
does that sound familiar to you does
that not sound like the first time
prophecy of the New Testament known as
the 70 week prophecy it is the 70 week
prophecy in which God foretold the
coming of his own son he had given a
probationary time period to the children
of Israel and basically says to them
listen at the end of this time period my
son is going to be lifted up above the
earth on wood and if you reject him you
will be cut off and a new people will be
brought about whose job it will be to
spread the gospel around the world if
you would be so far to say in it so I
want you to check this out from Genesis
1 to Genesis 6 we have a parallel of the
70 week prophecy the first time
to see of the Old Testament 120 years
parallels the first time prophecy of the
New Testament the 70 week prophecy if
you're with me so far
once again amen now Genesis chapter 7
covers the flood Genesis chapter 8
covers a flood Genesis chapter 9 chapter
10 when we get to Genesis chapter 11 we
have the introduction of the Tower of
Babel what was the Tower of Babel what's
that story all about it was about
rebellion it was a lot of people who's
whose sins ultimately were reaching unto
heaven Tower of Babel we're gonna use
cert the throne of God we're gonna go up
to heaven and find a way to avoid any
other kind of punishment that God would
pour out upon us like he did in the
flood
so the Tower of Babel the Tower of Babel
the Tower of Babel a symbol of rebellion
a symbol of a people whose sins have
reached unto heaven and I have a
question for you is there a time
prophecy in the Bible that points to a
power that is symbolically represented
by the Tower of Babel whose sins also
reach unto heaven is there yes or no
absolutely and the time prophecy that
points that out is something called the
1260 year time prophecy time times and
1/2 where this power called Mystery
Babylon rises on the scene and is
seeking to reach where heaven to usurp
the authority of God are you with me so
far
Genesis chapters 1 through 6 parallel
the 70 weeks Genesis chapter 11 is a
snapshot in seed a parallel of the 1260
years in which Babylon rises and seeks
to usurp the authority of God
okay that's Genesis chapter 11 now at
the end of Genesis chapter 11 now I want
you to see this with me Genesis chapter
11 please notice with me Genesis chapter
11 and verse 29
or rather verse 27 now these are the
generations of Tara Tara begat Abram
Nahor and Haran and Haran begat lot and
Haran died before his father Terah in
the land of his Nativity in ur of the
Chaldees anyone know what or of the cow
these is where is that Babylon okay very
good and Abraham and they her took them
wives the names of Abraham's wife was
Sara the name of NARAS Nahor's wife was
Milkha the daughter of Haran and the
father of Milcah and the father of iske
but Sarai was barren she had no children
and Terah took Abram Abram his son and
lot the son of Haran his son son and
Sarah his daughter-in-law
his son Abraham's wife and they went
forth with them from ur of the counties
to go into the land of Canaan I have a
question for you did God call Abraham
where did he call him out of where did
he call him out of he called him out of
Babylon I have a question for you is
there a time prophecy in the Bible that
designates God calling his people out of
Babylon yes or no what time prophecy is
that the 2300 day time prophecy so guys
watch this now from Genesis in Genesis
chapter 6 you have the first time
prophecy in the Old Testament which
caramels what in the New Testament it
parallels the 70 week prophecy when we
get to Genesis 11 we have this seed or
this snapshot of the Tower of Babel a
symbol of rebellion against God which
parallels in the New Testament what
the 1260 with the rise of spiritual
Babylon and then in Genesis at the end
of Genesis 11 you have God calling a
people of Babylon to go to the land of
Canaan which parallels what time
prophecy the 2300 day time prophecy
beloved did you know that this movement
was foreshadowed in the Bible not just
in Daniel chapter 8 verse 14 but beloved
actually in many places in the scripture
and this is one of them because remember
Abraham was called to produce a great
multitude I hope that this quietness is
the Adventist version of excitement and
I have grown to learn that that the way
that Adventist get excited is by being
quiet
it's a quiet version of excitement so
I'm gonna be quiet with you just for a
moment
because I am really excited amen
so God calls a people out of Babylon to
produce a great multitude now watch this
because remember this is Genesis chapter
11 and then watch this Genesis 11 he's
crawled out of a call out of Babylon and
then watch this in Genesis 12 he is
given a promise he's told listen the
Promised One is coming no no no did you
catch that just now after calling them
out of Babylon that call out of Babylon
is
anonymous with a promise of a coming son
yes yes yes amen and listen beloved in
1844 when the promise was given that
Jesus will return again everyone was
excited because yes October 1844 it's
going to happen and then on October 22
1844 the Sun the Promised One did not
come but not a problem because we are
people of faith and God's Word said it
that settles it
we believe it that settles it amen you
ants in 1844 is Jesus coming again
everyone said no no no they didn't say
yes
everyone said let's pretend that we're
in 1844 and we are really excited about
hearing it and everyone said right right
right
that was 1844 I need you to help me now
okay just pull just just do 18:44
everyone said everyone all right all
right
1850 rolls around listen guys it's Jesus
coming again no no no you still got to
do your amens guys everyone Jesus coming
again yes yes yes why because look
listen listen listen guys Jesus word
God's Word is faithful God said it and
we believe it eighteen ninety rolls
around Jesus is coming again amen he may
be late but he's always on time nineteen
fifty jesus is coming again
a little lower please Jesus is coming
again yeah about right 1980 Eamonn I can
give you an amen to that y2k amen amen
amen amen
mm amen
2010 2015-2019 yeah yeah yeah nice try
because when we hear that now many of us
laugh inside yeah we laugh not now we're
good Adventists so we know you're not
supposed to laugh at that but the issue
is what we're saying is look my parents
thought that and their parents thought
that and their parents thought that and
it hasn't happened so we say amen amen
but in reality we're laughing we have
come to the place where we are now
doubting the word of God and we don't
say that without the Word of God but
just by the way we live just by the way
we we treat one another just by the way
we act as Christians it says we're
laughing on the inside because didn't
our other didn't our earlier generations
say he was coming and didn't this one
say he was coming like haven't we said
the song and I want you to imagine this
struggle because check this out remember
Abraham has been told you're going to be
the father of a great nation you're
going to be have a great multitude his
name Abraham means father of many and
can you imagine he has no son wait what
is
naming again father of many okay where
are the many that must have been an
embarrassing thing but I want you to
think about some of our churches we are
supposed to be the people who have been
called and I got a name change to
signify you didn't catch that I'm giving
you a new name seventh-day adventists I
mean Abraham and this name signifies
your mission you're going to be the
you're going to be the the the people
who bring about a great multitude okay
well where's the great multitude look at
our churches where is the great
multitude really really beloved I want
you to listen to the words that God
speaks to Abraham but to Sarah because
he says it's anything too hard for the
Lord like this message today is designed
to get us to stop laughing to get us to
stop doubting the word that God has said
it is to get us to understand that he is
coming again the promised son is coming
have faith believe it's going to happen
I know right now it looks like an
impossibility as impossible as Sarah I
was thinking how am I gonna have a child
of this old age I believe when I was
younger but I've grown all now and I
know that and we kind of have that
attitude sometimes beloved to me it's
it's so mind-blowing that this is in the
Bible how is our story in the first 18
chapters of the book of Genesis how is
that how is it that the very thing the
very parallel the very events that
happened in Genesis 1 to 18 how is it
that
parallels what God's endtime movement
would go through you mean God was
thinking about us don't laugh guys this
is not made-up stuff we have not
believed cunningly devised fables you
are not an Adventist by accident if you
ever doubt the word that God gave us
when he began when he started this
movement don't doubt it he's showing you
listen I know what I'm doing he's coming
but check this out because it gets
sweeter come back with me to Genesis 18
so in Genesis 18
we're gonna go to verse verse verse 15
right and this is the verse we left off
then Sarah denied saying our last not
for she was afraid and she said nay and
he said nay but now did laugh so he
confronts her you did laughs you don't
believe you are doubting we need to face
our reality amen don't deny yes faster
I'm struggling with belief yes faster
I'm wondering if I gave everything up
for nothing I'm struggling
God says face yourself but then he says
also listen to my word acknowledge it
out but I'm trying to get rid of your
doubt don't pretend don't pretend
so now check this out
here's what happens next verse 16 then
the man arose from thence and look
towards Sodom and Abraham went with them
to bring them on the way and the Lord
said should I hide from Abraham the
thing that I do
seeing that Abraham says surely become a
great and mighty nation and all the
nations of the earth shall be blessed in
him for I know him he will command his
children in his household after him and
they shall keep the way of the Lord to
do justice and judgment that the Lord
may bring upon Abraham that which he has
spoken of him and the Lord said because
the cry of Sodom and Gomorrah
great and because their sin is very
Grievous I will go down now and
investigate
okay I've often been told pastor you
have to give us like 10 seconds to catch
up so we can think so I'm going to give
you your 10 seconds is everyone ready
you guys the in 120 years parallels 70
weeks Tower of Babel parallels 1260
calling out of Babylon and being told
that you're going to produce a great
multitude and that the promised son is
coming and at that time God says to
Abraham now Abraham while I'm letting
you know that the Sun is coming in the
meantime I gotta let you know something
else a judgment has begun I am going
down to judge Sodom and Gomorrah to see
what's going on there and now check this
out so so what is he trying to do he
wants Abraham to be aware of the work
that he is about to do I'm about to
judge the earth and Abraham's response
what is it
yes Sodom and Gomorrah that wicked city
does he respond like Jonah whoo yes yes
it's time destroy the city
how does Abraham respond
Abraham begins the work of intercession
beloved listen to me if you want to know
what we as a church should be doing
while we are waiting for the coming of
the promised son it's right here
Abraham begins this work of intercession
if they're fifty will you spare it
if they're forty-five will you spare it
and he goes on and on pleading with God
for lost souls in other words beloved it
is as if Abraham has been given the
Ministry of reconciliation wait so how
many men came to see Abraham how many
angels because they were all angels I'm
giving you your ten seconds okay there
were three messengers and two of them
went ahead oh my that's what I said
oh my and the third one you guys if you
have ever doubted this message I need
you to stop laughing right now we have
not believed cunningly devised fables
how is this stuff in the Bible how is
what we have been preaching from the
book of Revelation chapter 14 how is our
history the rise of our movement and the
history that followed on our mission how
is all this in Genesis chapters one day
how is that possible divine design
beloved this to me is evidence of the
power of God's Word
this to me is evidence of the existence
of a supernatural being named God
because man could not do this three
angels to go ahead and with the third
one comes destruction by fire you're not
feeling me when the third one arrives
who we know to be God Himself when the
third one arrives there is destruction
with fire so it is this third angel you
understand what I mean when I say third
angel I'm talking about third messenger
who happened to be God Himself not a
created being but God Himself says to
Abraham listen this is the closing work
it is the work of reconciliation isn't
that what we've been given the Ministry
of reconciliation but here's the problem
guys how do we expect to reconcile the
world to God when we cannot even
reconcile amongst ourselves what
authority can we have to reconcile the
world to God when we cannot even
reconcile amongst ourselves
it is hypocrisy you cannot reconcile if
you don't have the spirit of love in you
and this is what Abraham had flowing
through his veins when he heard about
these people who were blaspheming God
and cursing God enough for God Himself
to come down and go destroy the city
what is Abraham doing he's pleading he's
pleading listen guys he's not pleading
for the fifty righteous you didn't catch
that he wasn't pleading for the forty
five or even for the ten he was not
pleading for them he was simply saying
hey will you spare the whole city if
there's ten righteous in it Wow Wow
what kind of love are we to have for the
world should we love the world yeah God
so loved the world not God so loved the
church God so loved the world so you got
to understand its beloved because what
the position God has put us in it is a
tremendous an honor it's a tremendous
position listen do you think God follows
his own advice what do you think so so
if if God follows his own advice then
how are we supposed to reconcile let me
ask you does it hold hold that question
for a second and let me go to this
question how when you have an issue with
someone how do you reconcile what do you
do you you Matthew 18 you go to the
person yourself and if they don't hear
you then what do you do
you take one or two witnesses with you
and if they don't hear you then what do
they do or they don't hear them then
what do you do you
bring it before the church that's the
process does God follow his own process
absolutely you see beloved Jesus had an
issue with mankind yes or no so what did
he do you can laugh
what did he do he came himself there's a
prophecy for that by the way it's called
the 70 weeks hey friends humans I have
an issue with you
see we you have sinned against me
and what did mankind do they killed them
we're not listening to you so they put
them to death 70 week prophecy now you
know G is not going to give up so hey
you reject me
I'm gonna send two witnesses did he send
two witnesses what were those two
witnesses there's a prophecy for that by
the way because how long did the to
witness prophesy 1260 years well did the
world hear the two witnesses what did
they do with them they killed them
Revelation chapter 11 French Revolution
two witnesses put to death they rejected
the two witnesses now check this out
since they have rejected Christ and then
they rejected the two witnesses then the
world has one more chance take it before
the church
but God needs a church so what does he
do he raises up an entire movement and
Abraham no no oh yeah ten seconds and
Abraham at least a church that is to be
like Abraham but beloved to a large
degree what you have happening now is
that we are fighting with each other
instead of interceding for a lost world
so now we're fighting over all these
issues in the church I don't have to
name those issues you know what those
issues are I've been involved in that
fight myself no no this way no no this
way and beloved listen there's a there's
a place to address these things but
beloved when it becomes the forefront
when it takes over the mission we have
lost sight of our purpose because the
bottom line is we have to understand
that till the end of time there is going
to be wheat and tear in the church and
there's not much we can do about it it's
going to happen so at some point we have
to start saying listen God called us
here to intercede for a lost world and
beloved let me tell you it's a strange
thing how when we begin to intercede for
a lost world how you can begin to come
together and the things that once
separated you you now find whoa
what are we doing as a church we are
spinning our wheels while a world is
perishing in their sins the infighting
and all this stuff happening in the
church and it's so crazy because despite
that God is still blessing the church we
are still growing rapidly not as rapidly
as we should be growing but we are still
growing how much more effective could
this church be if we realized what's
going on here in Genesis 1 Genesis
chapters 1 to 18 you see beloved this
investigative judgment is really about
what how do we respond to crisis God was
trying to see Abraham with it I'm gonna
go destroy the city Abraham what are you
going to do and Abraham is immediately
like okay what can we how can we work
together God to - to save as many as
possible in a sense God is judging
Abraham and in a sense Abraham takes on
the very attributes of the Savior who
became our intercessor this is in the
Bible guys stop laughing
God is trying to show us what it takes
to pass the judgment come I'm gonna
we're gonna we're gonna just just come
with me to the book of Genesis and I
need you to see something else because
we're gonna come back to this story but
I need you to follow this carefully come
with me to Genesis 27 this is still
going right in line with what we've been
talking about Genesis chapter 27
Genesis chapter 27 and and I want you to
notice with me
verse 1 in Genesis 27 and verse 1 we're
talking about the judgment we're talking
about us being down here at the end of
time and what is God trying to get his
people to see he's trying to get us to
stop laughing he's trying to get us to
understand that we have not believed
cunningly devised fables and he's trying
to show us through these stories let me
tell you something beloved the Word of
God is multi-dimensional there are so
many layers to this thing and we often
cut ourselves off from a deeper
understanding of the Word of God because
we treat the Word of God as a shallow
thing Genesis 27 and it came to pass
that when Isaac was old and his eyes
were dimmed so that he could not see he
called Esau his eldest son and said unto
him my son and he said Behold here am I
and he said behold now I am old and I
know not the day of my death you guys
know this story right you have Isaac you
have Jacob you have Esau and you have
Rebekah and who is Isaac's favorite Esau
and in the story
Isaac is about to bless Esau I need you
to listen to this who do we have in this
story there are four characters Isaac
Esau Rebecca
Jacob okay tell me about Jacob what does
he want in this story he wants the
blessing he wants the blessing amen
anybody in here want the blessing amen
who is Isaac he is the father who is
Esau
who who is Esau he is the first born the
beloved of his father for a moment I
want you to forget about the names in
this story are you with me
forget about Esau and his wickedness
forget about Isaac and his favoritism
forget about Jacob and his deceptions
forget about Rebekah just look at the
characters of the story you have the
father the firstborn the beloved a
helper you didn't guess I think you
is there a helper in the story who is
the helper Rebekah Abraham's help me
watch this and you have one who desires
the blessing one who wants with
everything he has to receive the
blessing promised by God now now now
let's keep reading so the Bible says
Rebekah verse 6 read that or verse 5 and
Rebekah heard so the helper overhears a
conversation between the father and the
son
and what that helper years the helper
then turns to the one who is seeking the
promise of God does that story sound
familiar it should sound familiar
because guess what guys how many of you
want the blessing of God and how many of
you know that the only way you can get
it is through the helper so so watch
this so so when Rebecca heard Isaac
speak to his son Esau verse 5 and he so
I went to the field to hunt for venison
and to Brian and Rebekah spake unto
Jacob her son saying behold I heard thy
father speak unto Esau thy brother
saying bring me venison and make me say
every meet that I may eat and bless thee
before the Lord before my death now
therefore my son obey my voice according
to that which I command thee go now to
the flock and fetch me from thence to
good kid to the goats and I will make
them savory meat for thy father such as
he loveth and thou shalt breed that I
father that he may eat and that he will
bless thee before his death and Jacob
said to Rebekah his mother behold mother
you are crazy behold Esau my brother is
a hairy man and I am a smooth man my
father peradventure will what will what
will feel me and I will seem to him as a
deceiver and I served in a curse upon me
and not a blessing and his mother said
unto him upon me be thy curse my son
only obey my voice and go fetch me there
now is this a messed-up story in the
Bible this is a mess of sorry yes and
but never listen to me
even in the messed up stories you can
find dimensions of the plan of salvation
because all things work together for the
good of those that love God so so here's
what happens check the saw guys so
Rebecca listen carefully Rebecca uses
Rebecca tells Jacob we just gotta read
it come okay notice with me verse okay I
think my page is turning ok verse verse
15 and Rebecca took goodly remnants of
her eldest son Esau which was with her
in the house and put them upon Jacob her
younger son and she put the skins of the
kids of the goats upon his hand and upon
the smooth of his neck pause for a
second what is J what is Rebekah doing
here what's her plan
her plan what she's telling Jacob is
that in order to get the blessing you
have to be covered in the garments of
the first born I am slowly packing up
because I'm excited right now in order
for you to stand before the father and
receive the blessing an animal must be
sacrificed and cover you so that when
you go in before the Father he will not
see you he's gonna see his beloved son
okay okay okay
so Jacob buys into this and you can
imagine him shaking his head like mom
what are you doing he goes and watch
this and in verse 26 and his father
verse 25 or verse 24 verse 20 first 22
verse 21 oh my I'm sorry guys forgive me
I'm just excited we're going to go to
verse 19 you know I'm in verse 18 right
and he came unto his father and said My
Father and he said here am I who are
thou my son now if you remember earlier
in this story the Bible says that Isaac
was old and his eyes were dimmed praise
God his eyes were dimmed
he could not see praise God that the
father in the judgment dims his eyes
okay you want the blessing I'm gonna
close my eyes I'm gonna see I'm gonna
give you a chance to prove to me that
you are my son watch watch watch so so
it says and Isaac said unto his son how
is it
verse 19 Jacob said unto his father I'm
Esau thy firstborn whoa
I am Esau thy firstborn I have done
according as obvious me arise I pray
thee sit and eat my venison that I made
but as I saw me bless me and Isaac said
unto his son how is it that you found it
so quickly my son and he said because
the LORD thy God brought it to me Wow
and I said some of the Jacob he come
near I pray thee that I may steal thee
my son whether thou be my very son Esau
or not what what is Isaac doing here
he's investigating come here wait who
are you wait you're telling me crisis in
you really really okay come near to me I
want to feel you I want to feel your
hands and your neck I want to see if you
feel like my firstborn BLEVE you want
you want to pass the investigative
judgment you better have the hands of
Jesus you better have the hands of Jesus
you can imagine that Jacob must be
terrified
I'm standing before the father in my
imperfection and whooping praise God and
our Heavenly Father dims you get what I
mean when I say that yes that he deems
his eyes so at least give us a fighting
chance to stand in the garments of the
firstborn and say yes I am hidden in
Christ and so the fart the father calls
Jacob Colts and the Bible says in verse
22 and Jacob went near unto Isaac his
father and he felt him and he said the
voice is Tina's voice it's Frank's voice
it's Michaels voice it's Roxanne's voice
but the hands you know the hands of my
son these are helping hands these are
caring hands these are hands that are
ministering to those that are in need
these are the hands of my son and he
discerned him not because his hands were
hairy and his ass his brother Esau hands
so he blessed them and he said are gone
my very son Esau he's still not totally
convinced you can imagine that Jacob was
about to pass out and he said bringing
their to me and I will eat of my son's
venison that my soul may bless thee and
they brought it near the M&E and he did
eat and he brought him wine and he drank
and his father Isaac said unto him come
near now and kiss me my son
I mean it's can you imagine Jacob just
wants to get the blessing and get out of
there as fast as he can and the father's
like no no no no no no stay a while
because he's still not sure
and verse 27 says and he came near him
and he kissed them he like grabs him and
pulls him in and kisses him and he
smelled the smell of his rich I know how
I can tuck it let me smell you and he
said see the smell of my son is that the
smell of a field which the Lord has
blessed yeah it's none of my son
indicates and he's been in the field my
son is in the field
my son is bringing in the sheaves let me
smell you do you smell like you have
been in the field if you smell like
you've been in the field if you have my
hands then I know even in the midst of
stories of the Bible beloved Jesus is
there alright I want you to put that
analogy on pause and we're just gonna
totally flip the scene right now and I'm
gonna destroy I just want you to check
this out because listen as as Jacob is
standing before the father he's covered
in a what he's covered in a sacrifice he
is standing as a sacrifice before the
father to be accepted who does that
remind you of it reminds us of Jesus in
another sense Jacob himself is like a
type of Jesus standing before the Father
covered in a sacrifice receiving the
blessing now now watch this do you
remember this story that after Jacob
receives the blessing that he has to go
away
Jacob has to leave he receives the
blessing and then he goes away does that
sound familiar to you because after
Jesus's death burial and resurrection
does he go away yeah okay now watch this
while Jacob is away because remember he
was away for some time while he was away
he was doing two things he was working
for his bride do you need 10 seconds no
good good good when I asked that just
say go and I know that you got it you
say 10 oh wait
when Jacob stands before the Father as a
sacrifice after the sacrifice is
accepted he then is sent away he goes
away and while he is away he is not only
working for his bride but he's
multiplying to himself sons and
daughters not only is he doing that
he is also literally multiplying the
flock what check this out guys while he
is away he is doing three things he is
working for the bride
he's multiplying to himself sons and
daughters and he is multiplying the
flock is that not what we are supposed
to be doing while the heavenly Jacob has
entered Heaven Jesus right now in the
heavenly sanctuary is working for his
bride he is multiplying to himself sons
and daughters and he is literally
multiplying the flock but here's a
question the question is how did Jacob
multiply the flock
do you remember the story how Laban he's
getting ready to leave and labels like
no I want you to stay and then he says
okay you give me all the speckled cattle
and and that'll be my pay and then what
does Laban do he takes all the speckled
cattle away and and separates them three
days from the flock that he leaves with
Jacob so that Jacob has no speckled or
spotted cat or cats
so now Jacob has a problem because he
has nothing to leave me so you know what
he does check this out
come with me to Genesis to Genesis
chapter 28 Genesis chapter 28
or rather 27 I'm sorry Genesis chapter
27 nope nope it is Genesis chapter 20
oh no no no I'm sorry Genesis chapter 30
Genesis chapter 30 Genesis chapter 30
and verse 31 we'll go to verse 32 so the
Bible says here I will pass through all
I flock today removing from thence all
the speckled and spotted cattle and all
the brown cattle among the sheep and the
spotted and speckled among the goats and
such saviem are higher verse 35 verse 34
and Laban said Behold I would I wouldn't
it be might be according to my word and
he removed that day the he goats that
were ringed straight and spotted and all
the she goats that were speckled and
spotted and every one that had some
white in it and all the brown among the
sheep and gave them into the hands of
his sons and said three days journey how
many days everyone three days remember
that number three days journey betwixt
himself and Jacob and Jacob fed that fed
the rest of late of late onslaughts and
Jacob took him rods of green poplar and
of the hazel and chestnut tree and
peeled white streaks in them and made
the white appear which was in the rods
and his
set the rods which he had peeled before
the flocks in the gutters in the water
troughs where the thoughts came to drink
that they should conceive when they came
to drink and the floods conceived before
the rods and brought forth cattle
ringstraked speckled and spotted and
Jacob did separate the lands and set the
faces of the flats toward the
ringstraked and all the Brahman the
flock of the Lamb a flock of Laban and
he put his own flocks by themselves and
put them not unto Laban Seattle and it
came to pass when so ever the stronger
countably conceived that Jacob laid the
rods before their eyes before the eyes
of the cattle and the gutters that they
might conceive among the rods but when
the cattle were feeble he put them not
in so the feeble air were Levens and the
stronger were jacob's and the mane
increase exceedingly and had much cattle
and maidservants and men's servants and
camels and houses do you know what Jacob
did let me tell you when he and don't
try this at home because this was a
miracle watch this he takes branches he
takes wood
and he he puts stripes in the wood and
then he sets the wood before the cattle
that he wants to change so when the
cattle come together and they begin to
breed and their eyes were on the striped
wood by beholding by beholding they
became changed and I would listen to me
do you want our church to multiply do
would you like a church full of strong
Christians keep your eye on the Striped
would keep your eye on the cross of
Calvary where Jesus Christ took stripes
on our behalf that we might be healed
and strengthened you see beloved Satan
realized Satan does not care if we
multiply as long as we're not looking at
the striped wood you didn't catch that
because the flood that multiplied
without looking at the striped wood were
the weaker flock you want to be strong
look up you want to be strong look to
the cross
you want a strong church lift up Christ
and
crucify you want a strong Church
intercede for lost world through the
merits of Jesus Christ look to the
striped wood
the question is what are we beholding
because my beholding you become changed
so sin can take your attention off of
the striped wood
guess what you might be bringing 20 50
100 people into the church and in a
short time guess where they are out of
the church because we did not lift up
Jesus
we didn't lift up the cross notice
Layden kept his flock three days away
another that three day journey is a
symbol of Christ and him crucified Satan
wants to keep us three days away Satan
wants to keep us away from the cross he
wants to keep us away from the one that
died by whose stripes we are healed and
I'm telling you when as a church we
learn to focus on Christ and lift up
Christ that's gonna change that's gonna
change
sososo come notice with me Genesis
chapter 31 Genesis chapter 31 soul the
Bible says in verse 1 and there and they
and he heard the words of Laban son
saying Jacob at stake and all that was
our fathers and and of that which was
our fathers has he gotten all this glory
and Jacob beheld the countenance of
Laban and behold it was not toward him
as before notice verse 3 and the Lord
said unto Jacob return hold on
Jakub stands before the father as a
blessing that's a sacrifice after the
sacrifice is accepted he goes away
he goes away and while he is away he is
multiple heals working for his bride
multiplying to himself sons and
daughters multiplying the flock by
having them focus on the strike wood and
then the father says Jacob it's time to
return return return you don't catch
that let's go to Genesis 32 and Jacob
went on his way verse 1 and Jacob went
on his way and the angels of God met him
so not only did he return he was
returning with angels y'all not feeling
bad I've given you a retinue of angels
I've given you a of giving you an army
of angels return now how many of you
know the story here how many of you
remember what happens next
so Jacob sends a group of his people
because he hears that Esau is coming
after him
let me ask you a question why does Esau
think Jacob is coming why does he think
he's coming for what for warfare
he thinks he's coming to make good on
the promise that was given to him
remember the blessing wait he's coming
to take my stuff Esau believes that
Jacob is coming with with a vindictive
purpose son answer question does Esau
understand the nature and character of
his brother does he understand the
nature and character of the one who is
returning listen to me church there are
Esau's out in
the world who fear the second coming of
Jesus because they don't understand his
character they don't understand who he
really is
they think he's coming for one purpose
and for one purpose only and that is to
destroy but beloved the Bible says that
Jesus came to save
so Jacob hears this he hears that Esau
is coming with an army and I want you to
notice what he does come with me Genesis
chapter 32 Genesis 32 verse 13 so the
Bible says and he lodged there the same
night and took of that which came to his
hand a present for Esau his brother let
me ask you a question
a present for Esau his brother what does
Jacob trying to do here he's trying to
change the heart of Esau but then what
is our mission
are there Esau is out there in the world
that need to understand the true
character of Jesus so watch when Jacob
does so the Bible says he lodged there
the same night and took of that which
came to his hand a present for Esau his
brother
two hundred she-goats and 20 he goats
and two hundred ewes 20 rounds 30 mils
camels which with their coats forty kind
and ten bulls twenty ciasses and ten
foals and he delivered them into the
hand of his servants every juror of by
themselves and said unto his servant
pass over before me put a space betwixt
drove and drove and he commanded the
foremost saying when II saw my brother
cut me taffy and asked if these saying
whose art thou and whither boards down
and whose are these before thee then
thou shalt say they be thy servants
Jacobs it is a present seventh to my
lord Esau and behold
also he is behind us and so commanded he
the second and the third I'm gonna give
you ten seconds Jacob is now sending his
flock out to meet he saw there is a
messenger at the head
of the flock but he breaks them up
he sends three messengers and every
messenger is saying hey listen uh
basically we want you to know that Jacob
loves you but by the way he's behind us
he's coming he's coming they never
listen to me the three angels messages
were not designed to put fear in the
hearts of the world it was designed to
tell the world that the true fear of God
is to love him because he loves you and
when Jacob saw that this flock was
healthy and powerful not scrawny
not malnutrition but I healthy flock why
was a flock healthy because they had
been beholding striped wood when Esau
sees the the frock he's like whoa this
is blessed and you know what ends up
happening when Jacob finally gets to
Esau the Bible says they embraced
beloved in that story we have a snapshot
of how God wants to meet the Esau's of
the world he doesn't want to meet them
in in vengeance he wants to see for God
so loved the world that He gave His only
begotten Son that whosoever believeth in
him should not perish but have
everlasting life and he depends upon us
the flock to go before him to prepare
the way
for the coming one listen to me
I have ten minutes left now is about to
go into a whole nother section and I
don't even have time to do that so I'm
gonna wrap this up early instead of
going over late I need you to understand
something
Jesus is coming again
don't laugh stop laughing stop doubting
it's going to happen and beloved if our
hearts are not right with God we will
not be ready for that second coming in
fact do you remember earlier how I said
that Abraham thought that Ishmael was
the Promised One Abraham the father of
faith because his heart was not right he
was ready to receive an imposter twenty
seconds because his heart at that moment
was not right he was ready to see to
receive an imposter in the place of the
promised son
that Ishmael lived forever
he is the one and I know as Adventist we
always do that thing well we know that
when Satan comes his feet don't touch
the ground or when Jesus comes his feet
don't touch the ground so that's Satan
and let me tell you something you might
know that all you want and have faith in
that all you want but if your heart is
not right the overwhelming deception of
Lucifer himself appearing as Jesus will
lead you to the conclusion that you were
wrong at seventh-day adventists maybe
god's worried about giving me a son in
this way about bringing the son in this
way maybe it wasn't right because god
clearly said to abraham you Sarah will
have a son not someone else but Sarah
but maybe we got it wrong maybe we
should look for the promise in another
way and hey this looks like it we've
been waiting so long anyway
I mean maybe this is it maybe we were
wrong I know what you say now you say
the same thing Abraham would have said
before Hagar us never we shall trust in
the Word of God look how far we've come
we've can't we obeyed God's Word we came
out of Babylon we've done all these
things we trust God
but Abraham the father of faith because
his heart in that moment was not right
he was ready to receive an imposter in
the place of the true promise
beloved do not Pat yourselves on the
back thinking I'm an Adventist and I
know Bible truth because a mere mental
assent to truth will not hold you when
the overwhelming delusion takes place on
this earth Satan will soul flip things
that it will make your mind spin if your
heart is not right with God now as
the time to laugh there is coming a time
to laugh but now is not that time you
see sir I did have a son and his name
was Isaac and the name Isaac means
laughter and beloved when Jesus comes
again then it will be time to laugh not
a mocking laugh ha ha ha we told you no
but a rejoicing laugh wow it's here it's
happening we have not believed cunningly
devised fables it will be a holy all
righteous laugh then it will be turned
to laugh now is not the time to laugh
now is the time to pray now is the time
to reconcile now is the time to get our
hearts right with God now is the time to
love as Jesus loved now is the time to
cover yourselves in the garments of
Christ and then the sacrifice of Christ
so that when the father looks at you he
does not see you he sees Jesus now is
the time to smell like Jesus now is the
time to act like Jesus to walk like
Jesus to do as much as you can
now is the time beloved to intercede for
a world that is lost now is a time to
have faith like never before that the
promised son is indeed coming let's
start laughing is Jesus coming again do
you believe that Jesus is coming again
do you believe that Jesus is coming
again that needs to be an 1844 amen
again
[Applause]